Guide to the Children’s Service Guild Collection
2016 The Regents of the University of Nevada. All rights reserved.
TEST Repository
Children's Service Guild Collection
1947-1990
1971-1975 (bulk)
TEST Repository
Children’s Service Guild
MS-00334
2 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Acquisition Information:
Materials were donated in 1993 by Robert Ranney; accession number 1993-029.
Access:
This collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The Children's Services Guild is a volunteer group organized in 1969 to provide support for children through Clark County Family and Youth Services (formerly Juvenile Court Services). The group meets weekly to create craft items for sale at their Christmas boutique. The proceeds from sales of the crafts are available to the staff at Family and Youth Services to benefit children with needs over and above what would normally be provided, such as eyeglasses or special dental needs.
Scope and Contents Note
The Children's Service Guild Collection was donated by Robert Ranney, Director of Clark County Juvenile Court Services from 1981 to 1993. The collection was created by the guild. It contains numerous newspaper clippings concerning various aspects of juvenile crime, behavior, development, and programs. The collection also contains material pertaining to Clark County Juvenile Court Services.
Arrangement of the Records
The collection has been processed into four series:
Series 1. Juvenile Crime
Series 2. Miscellaneous Juvenile Topics
Series 3. Clark County Juvenile Court Services
Series 4. Scrapbooks
Separated Materials
Photographic material was removed from the collection as follows: 34 envelopes of negatives, 1 slide, 27 loose negatives, 21 proof sheets and 83 loose photographs (some of these photographs were the ones removed from the scrapbook).
Juvenile delinquency -- Nevada -- Clark County; Juvenile corrections -- Nevada -- Clark County; Juvenile courts -- Nevada -- Clark County; Children -- Services for -- Nevada -- Clark County; Children -- Nevada -- Clark County -- Social conditions; Nevada. Juvenile Court (Clark County). Services -- Records and correspondence; Children’s Service Guild; Children’s Service Guild
- Series I. Juvenile Crime, 1947-1990; (approximately 1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  The Juvenile Crime Series consists entirely of news clippings, organized by year. Some of the news clippings have been copied; others were retained as newsprint.
- Series 2. Miscellaneous Juvenile Topics, 1971-1974.; (2 boxes)
  The Miscellaneous Juvenile Topics Series consists of news clippings and press releases from 1971-1974. The year 1974 in particular has the most extensive material and is organized by detailed subject, with cross references to related subjects. The subjects include youths, crime, hotlines, law enforcement, abuse, drugs, prison, children’s liberation, behavioral services, welfare, etc. The folder headings and cross references to other folders are the same as those used by the Guild.
  - Child care, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Youth, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Group homes (see also: Ettie Lee, Regina Hall, Halfway House, Nike), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Law enforcement, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Runaways (Judy Carlos series), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Child abuse, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Crime (see also: phony IDs, drug abuse, law enforcement), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Drug abuse, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Art Besser, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Teen Ticket Tally, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - School Board, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Methadone (see also: drug abuse), undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Prisons (see also: corrections) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hotlines (incl. LV Operation Bridge, Houston Operation Peace of Mind), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Training, juvenile staff, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - John F. Mendoza, Juvenile Judge, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mental health, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Recycling plant, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Halfway House, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - State Welfare, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sammy Cohen, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Ettie Lee Home, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Zenoff Hall, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Funding, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Murder (incl. age limit), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Concerts, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Youth Conservation Corps, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - CHINS (see also: Runaways), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - So. Nevada Drug Abuse Council (see also: Drug abuse), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Schools (see also: School board), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Pregnancy Counseling Services, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Children's Behavioral Service, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Kid's Lib, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Regina Hall and So. Nevada Children's Home, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Law (children's rights), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Series 3. Clark County Juvenile Court Services, 1966-1982; (1 box)
  The third series, Clark County Juvenile Court Services, contains materials pertaining to the operation of the department – annual reports, employee handbook, and grand opening guest book. This material covers the period 1966-1982. A report by the Michigan Department of Social Services- Office of Children and Youth is also included.
  - Clark County Juvenile Court House groundbreaking article and grand opening, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Juvenile Court Services employee handbook, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Spring Mtn. Youth Camp and School, Annual Report, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Juvenile Court Services Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Michigan Dept. of Social Services, Office of Children and Youth, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series 4. Scrapbooks, 1963-1976; (1 box)
  There are two scrapbooks stored in box five. The black album contains news clippings about juveniles and crime related stories from 1974-1976. The gold album contains the emblem for Clark County and the State of Nevada. In addition, there are newspaper articles from 1963-1968 about juvenile activities, part of a Masonic lodge program, and some photographs. Many photographs had been cut out of the album prior to processing, but the captions remain.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1974-1976; (black album) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1963-1968; (gold album) (Box 5, Folder 2)